#### **GREGORY LEMIEUX**

#### gregory.lemieux@gmail.com 1-510-847-6519 glemieux.github.io

Astronautics professional with a broad technical backround working towards Computational Engineering degree. Excellent communicator within commercial, manufacturing and research environments; Proven ability to adapt to changing responsibilities based on evolving project requirements with a diverse skill set developed through participation in multiple stages of spacecraft design, development, and operations.

</>

## SKILLS

Scientific Programming Matlab/Simulink Julia Python C Fortran

Source Control Git SVN

## EMPLOYMENT

## Systems Engineering Specialist, SSL

Dynamics and Controls Engineering, Mission Analysis and Design

2012-04 - Present

- Developing next-generation orbit simulation code for future SSL mission validation and rehearsals.
- Responsible for the next-generation on-board flight software orbit estimation filter.
- Founding member of the Guidance, Navigation and Control Software Development Working Group.
- Built Julia and Jupyter-based mission analysis tools for future SSL missions.
- Mission analysis for the Restore-L program.

## Research and Development Engineer, Space Science Laboratory

Flight Engineer and Mission Scheduler for the THEMIS mission and ARTEMIS extension. 2008-06 — 2012-04

- Developed science data accumulation forecasting tool to aid in planning mission critical science collection.
- Integrated DSN Service Scheduling Software into active mission operation scheduling process.
- Scheduled ARTEMIS mission supports including critical Lunar Orbit Insertion.
- Contributed to the Deep Space Network Scheduling Advisory and Mid-range Management Groups.

## **Opto-mechanical Engineer, Janos Technology**

Designed infrared lens assemblies for commercial, defense, and research applications.

2003-12 — 2006-05

 Represented the engineering department as a member of the company-wide Quality Control Committee seeking AS9100 compliance.

## **Mechanical Engineer, Center for Space Physics**

Designed and developed the vacuum-sealed opto-mechanical assembly for the main science 2001-09-2003-06 payload for the SPIDR NASA SMEX mission proposal.

#### 1

#### **EDUCATION**

## M.S. Interdiscplinary Engineering, Purdue University

Part-time, customized, distance program with focus on Computational Engineering.

2017-01 — Present

## **B.S. Aerospace Engineering, Boston University**

\_\_\_\_1997-09 — 2002-05

#### K CED

## SERVICE

## Safety Implimentation Team Member, Unitarian Universalist Church of Berkeley

The Safety Implimenation Team is responsible for educating all church groups on the Safety Plan 2017-09 — Present requirements.

Trained Family Ministry and Religious Education Volunteers on Emergency Evacuation procedures.

## Social Media Team Member, Unitarian Universalist Church of Berkeley

Administrative member of the church Social Media Team. Responsible for training, technical 2018-07 — Present support, and analytics reporting to the church Program Council.

## **A**

## WRITING

## SSL Commercial Geosynchronous Spacecraft Orbit Raising Considerations, Univelt

Survey findings from all SSL launches since the 1990s.

2016

# THEMIS Mission Networks Expansion - Adding the Deep Space Network for the ARTEMIS Lunar Mission Phase, Space Ops Conferences

Discussion of the integration of the Deep Space Network software and processes for the ARTEMIS mission 2010 extension.

## •

## RECOGNITION

## Asterism Award. SSL

Peer-to-peer recognition for developing and delivering introductory training material for new orbit dynamics 2015 group employees.

## Apogee Award, SSL

Received for contributions to a 2013 NASA Institute for Advanced Concepts (NIAC) proposal for a deep space 2013 communications architecture concept.

## ARTEMIS Extension, NASA

For work on lunar ARTEMIS extension.